(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T16:53:33.779205",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
この声をあなたに届けるために 私は叫び続ける
To deliver this voice to you, I will keep screaming.
風に吹かれて
Blown by the wind,
誰も気づかぬように
so that no one notices,
区別がつかない
unable to tell apart
モノクロの世界
a monochrome world.
色を足しても
Even if I add color,
何も見えなくて
I can see nothing at all,
まるです私は
as if I
息を止めていた
had been holding my breath.
もういいよ
It's fine now,
遠くても 叶えたい 私は
even if it's far, I want to make it real—
こんな世界 想いも抱きしめていたいのに
even though I want to hold my feelings close in this world,
夢のキャンバスに 居続ける意味はこの胸に 輝いている ストーリー
the reason to stay on the canvas of dreams shines in my heart: my story.
差し伸べた
I reached out my hand...
風に吹かれて 誰も気づかぬように
Blown by the wind, as if no one notices,
区別がつかない モノクロの世界
in a monochrome world where nothing stands out.
色を足しても 何も見えなくて
Even adding colors, I couldn't see a thing,
まるで私は 息を止めていた
it was as if I had stopped breathing.
もういいよ
It's fine now.
遠くても 叶えたい 私は
Even if it's far, I want to make it come true—
こんな世界 想いも抱きしめていたいのに
even though I want to embrace my feelings in this world.
夢のキャンバスに 居続ける意味は
What is the meaning of staying on the canvas of dreams?
この胸に 輝いている ストーリー
A story shines brightly in this heart of mine.
与えることに 意味などないけど
There's no real meaning in giving, but
拾い集めた カケラ失うの?
am I losing the fragments I gathered up?
そして夜は その冷たさを
And at night, I reached out my hand,
溶かして手を 伸ばした
melting away that coldness.
もういいよ
It's fine now.
遠くても 届けたい 私は
Even if it's far, I want to reach it—
受け止めてく 涙も抱きしめていたいのに
even though I want to hold close the tears I accept.
そして夜は その冷たさを
And at night, I reached out my hand,
溶かして手を 伸ばした
melting away that coldness.
もういいの
It's fine now.
遠くても 叶えたい 私の
Even if it's far, I want to make it come true—
こんな世界 想いも言葉で包んだ
wrapping my feelings in words in this kind of world.
夢のキャンバスに 色を足していく
Adding colors to the canvas of dreams,
この胸に 今輝いて
shining now in this heart of mine.
強くなくてもいい 壊れかけてもいい
It's okay not to be strong, it's okay to break apart.
この心は 永遠に羽ばたいて
This heart will soar forever,
響くように 塗り替えていく パレット
repainting the palette so it resonates.
はい！あけましておめでとうございます！
Hi! Happy New Year!
ふぅ、ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです。
Whew, I'm Tokoyami Towa of Hololive 4th Gen.
はい、ということで皆さん緊張しております。
So, everyone, I'm so nervous.
常闇トワ 2周年なんですね、今日は。
Today is Tokoyami Towa's 2nd anniversary.
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
配信始まる前からいっぱい素敵なコメントいただき
I received so many wonderful comments even before the stream started,
もうめっちゃ緊張したんだよ、な、いま。
and I was super nervous just now.
ほんとにすごい緊張するんですよ。
I really get so nervous.
なんたって、ていうか、あの、なんない人のほうが多いかもしれないけど
I mean, maybe most people don't get this nervous, but
トワちょっと休止してて、あ、ちょっと無理だ、休むわ、って言って
Towa took a little break and said, "Ah, this is too much, I need to rest," and
今日、久しぶりの配信なんです！
today is my first stream back in a while!
やっほー！ありがとう！
Yahoo! Thank you!
はい、1発目、「Palette」歌いました、これね。
Yes, for the first song, I sang "Palette".
「劇場版エンディング」とか言われてて、すごい光栄なんですけれども。
People were calling it a "theatrical anime ending," which is such an honor.
エンディングではなく、今回オープニングで歌わせてもらいました！
Instead of an ending, I got to sing it as the opening this time!
もう演出とかもね、すごくこだわって…
We were really particular about the production and staging...
そう、「Palette」はね、結構思い出がある曲でして
Yeah, "Palette" is a song with a lot of memories for me,
まあ、いろんなものと出会って、前に進んでいくっていう曲なので
and it's a song about encountering various things and moving forward,
まあ1発目にこの曲を持ってきて、エモい感じにしてみました！
so I wanted to bring this song as the first one with an emotional vibe!
で、なんと、なんと、なんと、みんなステージ見てくれた？
And guess what, everyone, did you check out the stage?
ステージ、見て、BBと、あと見て
Look at the stage, BB, and look—
おい、TMTって書いてある！あのでっかい電光掲示板みたいなの。
Hey, it says "TMT"! On that huge electronic billboard.
あれ、あの曲名載せてくださいねって言ったんだけど、なんかTMTって書いてある。
I asked them to put the song title there, but it says "TMT".
よく分からんって！これね、あのステージなんですけれど、フォントから、あの3Dでフォントを作ってくださった方がいて
I have no idea why! Anyway, for this stage, someone made 3D fonts from scratch,
これちょっとモチーフ使用していいですかってリップしたら
and when I asked if I could use their motif,
「え、どうぞどうぞ！トワ様もどうぞ！」っていう形で使わせて
they said, "Sure, go ahead! Towa-sama, please do!" and let me use it as reference.
参考にしてね、作っていただきましたーー！
They made it for me based on that!
おい、TMTコメント多すぎだろ！
Hey, there are way too many "TMT" comments!
はい、あと今日のハッシュタグがこちら、常闇トワ2周年記念、常闇トワ2周年記念
Right, and today's hashtags are #TokoyamiTowa2ndAnniversary...
はい、になってます！これね、いっぱい呟いて、新年からトレンド入りさせてくれたらうれしいです！
Please tweet a lot and get it trending from the start of the year!
可愛いよね、あのさ
It's so cute, you know,
ホロライブのさ、ボイスでさ、ハロウィンボイスが出たときに
back when the Hololive Halloween voice packs came out,
たまたまね、トワの、トワがそのハロウィンボイスの絵だったんだけど、
as it happened, Towa was featured in the Halloween voice art,
それをチョコ先生が描いてくれてて、「うわ、めっちゃ素敵なイラストだ」と思って、もうお願いしちゃいました！
and Choco-sensei drew it for me! I thought, "Wow, what a wonderful illustration," and just asked her!
もうありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
あとロゴもね、はい、ロゴはね、ホロライブ好きになったら結構見るんじゃないでしょうか？
And the logo too—yes, the logo is something you see quite often if you like Hololive, right?
ヒーラギ先生に描いていただきました！作ってもらいました、ありがとうございます！
Hiiragi-sensei drew it for me! They made it for me, thank you so much!
はい、まあ軽く、軽くなっちゃうんですけども、紹介もしまして、
Right, well, keeping it brief, after introducing that,
このあとはね、一曲歌って、ライブということで、もっともっといっぱいあるので、楽しんでいってください！
we'll sing a song and have a live performance next, there's so much more, so please enjoy!
はい！まだまだ楽しんでもらって、
Yes! Keep having fun,
いけば……あれっ、
and go—wait,
言葉がぐちゃぐちゃじゃないか。
my words are all jumbled up.
はい、このあともね、楽しんでください！ということで、次はなんと！
Right, please enjoy the rest of the show too! So, next up is...
ゲストパートー！
A guest segment!
少しずつ近づいているよ 夢に見たトキメキ
Getting a little closer, the excitement I dreamed of.
広がっていく世界中に 皆を笑顔にするキラメキを
Spreading across the whole world, the sparkle that makes everyone smile.
一人じゃないから ライバルがいるから
Because I'm not alone, because there are rivals,
競い合うことすら 楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
even competing with each other becomes so much fun!
dear my friends
未来へ走り出したら fantastic 夢を咲かせて our future
when we run toward the future, fantastic, let our dreams bloom, our future.
一歩一歩を踏み出して トップを目指そう
Taking step by step, let's aim for the top!
信じる力が心の happiness 全力で楽しもう
The power to believe is the heart's happiness, let's enjoy it with all our might!
それはいつかきっと
That will surely, someday,
大きな夢叶えるから
fulfill our big dreams,
dreaming days
答えのない道を行く 誰も見たことのない世界
Walking a path with no answers, a world no one has ever seen.
連れて行くよ 皆の事 覚悟は良いかな？手を離さないで
I'll take you along, are you ready? Don't let go of my hand.
一人じゃないから 君が見ているから
Because you're not alone, because you are watching.
初めての挑戦すら 楽しくなっちゃうんだよ
Even a first challenge becomes so much fun!
daydream believe
( yeah ! ! )
(Yeah!!)
奇跡を巻き起こすんだよ glorious 夢に近づいて my story
stirring up miracles, glorious, getting closer to my dreams, my story.
とても小さな蕾が花咲かせるまで
Until a very small bud blooms into a flower,
挑戦し続けるんだ brilliant 全力で飛び込もう
continuing to challenge ourselves, brilliant, let's dive in with all our might!
ほんの少しだけの
Just a tiny bit of
勇気が今をくれたんだ
courage gave us the present moment.
dreaming days
選んできた未来の選択肢 全てがほら私を作った
Every choice of the future I've made has shaped who I am, look.
選ぶことの無かった過去さえ 大事な意味があったと気づいたよ
Even the pasts I didn't choose, I realized they had important meanings.
涙を流した数が emotion 熱い心が over heat
The number of tears I shed is emotion, a passionate heart is over heat.
本気だからこそ思える トップになりたい！
Because I'm serious, I can feel it—I want to reach the top!
未来へ走り出したら fantastic 全力で楽しもう
When we run toward the future, fantastic, let's enjoy it with all our might!
それはいつかきっと
That will surely, someday,
大きな夢叶えるから
fulfill our big dreams,
dreaming days
oh yeah
走り続けていくんだgrateful 一人じゃ届かない高みへ
Continuing to run, grateful, toward heights I couldn't reach alone.
( yeah ! ! )
(Yeah!!)
少しだけの勇気が今をくれたんだ dreaming days
Just a little bit of courage gave us the present moment, dreaming days.
選んできた未来の選択肢 全てがほら私を作った
Every choice of the future I've made has shaped who I am, look.
選ぶことの無かった過去さえ 大事な意味があったと気づいたよ
Even the pasts I didn't choose, I realized they had important meanings.
涙を流した数が emotion 熱い心が over heat
The number of tears I shed is emotion, a passionate heart is over heat.
本気だからこそ思える トップになりたい！
Because I'm serious, I can feel it—I want to reach the top!
未来へ走り出したら fantastic 全力で楽しもう
When we run toward the future, fantastic, let's enjoy it with all our might!
それはいつかきっと
That will surely, someday,
大きな夢叶えるから
fulfill our big dreams,
dreaming days
oh yeah
走り続けていくんだgrateful 一人じゃ届かない高みへ
Continuing to run, grateful, toward heights I couldn't reach alone.
( yeah ! ! )
(Yeah!!)
やー！
Yay!
え、かわいい、とわたち！
Aw, Towa and the others are so cute!
え、かわいかった！
Aw, that was so cute!
よかった！
I'm so glad!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
とわ、先輩！2周年、おめでとう！
Towa-senpai, happy 2nd anniversary!
うわー！すごい！
Woohoo! Amazing!
すごい、コラボ1発目にドエモいのを持いきてしまいました！
We brought such an extremely sexy song for our first collab!
いや、エモ、ほんとにエモい。なんか「ラスト」みたいな感じだったけどね、ほんとに。「ラスト」みたいな響きの曲だから、なんかすごく切なくなった。
Yeah, so emotional, truly emotional. It felt kind of like a "finale," you know? Since it's a song with a "finale"-like ring to it, it made me feel really bittersweet.
なんか歌えた！
But we got to sing it!
なんか、いいのかな、どうしようかなって思ったけど、やっぱりこういう1発目に「ボーン」っていうのを持ってきたら、ねぇ？ なんでこんな1発目に選ばれちゃいましたね、選ばれちゃった！ありがとう、呼んでくれてありがとう！
I was wondering if it's okay, what should I do, but bringing something with a bang right at the start like this... right? Why was this chosen for the very first song? We got chosen! Thank you so much for inviting me!
よかった、よかった！呼んでくれて本当にありがとう！
I'm so glad! Thank you so much for having us!
そう、相当不思議なメンバーじゃん？ なんでこのメンバーになった理由を...
Yeah, it's a pretty unusual member lineup, right? So let's talk about why we ended up with this group...
いや、そう、まず、そうだね、あずき先輩とは本当に歌がすごい好きで、一緒に歌いたかったんだけど、やっぱり2人とかで歌うのは、やっぱり、とわもドキドキしちゃうし、コラボとかも、誘いたくても誘えないくらいちょっとドキドキしてたから、ちょっと勇気を出して誘ってみて...
Well, first, yeah, with AZKi-senpai, I really love her singing and wanted to sing together, but singing just the two of us made Towa really nervous, and even for collaborations, I was too nervous to even invite her, so I mustered up the courage to invite her...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あとは、ねねねとロボ子先輩は、あの、周年配信とか、あの、誕生日配信の記念配信のときに、呼びたかったんだけど、今までまだちょっと呼べてなかったから、今回、今日ね、一緒に歌いたいですって、やっと呼べました！やった！やっと呼べた！ありがたい！ありがたい！
And for Nenene and Roboco-senpai, I wanted to invite them during my anniversary stream or my birthday commemoration stream, but I hadn't been able to invite them yet, so today I finally got to say I wanted to sing together with you guys! Yay! I finally got to invite you! I'm so grateful! Grateful!
いや、もう本当にこう、もうハーモニーもすごくよかったし！よかったね！すごくよかった！
Seriously, the harmonies were really wonderful too! It was great! Really great!
1曲目からね、ちょっとね、エモすぎて、もうなんちゃってなっちゃう、本当に出会えて幸せものだなってこんな。
Right from the first song, it's just so emotional, it's almost too much, I really feel like such a lucky person to have met you all.
え、今ドラもすごかった！今ドラも歌ってもらえてすごい、長めでよかった！
And "Imadora" was amazing too! Getting to sing "Imadora" as well was great, having a longer version was wonderful!
めっちゃよかったね！あの、降りてくるところもすごいよかったね！サビのところめっちゃめちゃ可愛かった！そう、1人ずつね、そう！めっちゃ可愛かったよ、みんな！
It was so good! The part where we walked down was really nice too! The chorus part was super cute! Yeah, one by one, yeah! Everyone was so cute!
これはね、本当にみなさんのおかげです！ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！こちらこそ、ここに出会えて本当によかった！ありがとう！
This is truly thanks to everyone! Thank you so much! Thank you! No, thank you, we're so glad we got to be here! Thank you!
ではね、次もあるということで。そう、まだ始まったばかり！
Well then, there's more to come. That's right, it has only just begun!
そう、こんなエモいだけじゃなくて、おわりの始まりの写真も、こうやって撮って。あ、撮りました！お疲れ様でした！集まれ、集まれ！
Yeah, not just emotional stuff, but we also took a photo at the start of the end like this. Ah, we took it! Good work, everyone! Gather around, gather around!
ありがとう！この後もお楽しみに！いえーい！
Thank you! Look forward to what's coming next! Yay!
でいり～だいあり～！
Daily diary!
青春実況中
Broadcasting my youth live
朝戦配信中
Streaming morning battles
青春実況中 朝戦配信中
Broadcasting my youth live, streaming morning battles
ほらね、楽しいを
Look, let's find
発見 まだ新しい好きが見つかったよ
and discover brand new things we love!
近所にできたカフェのケーキ
The cake from the new cafe in the neighborhood
なんかすごく美味し買ったんだよ
tasted somehow exceptionally delicious!
知らなかったゲームや
Games and such I never knew,
新曲 聞いたことない歌
and new songs I'd never heard before—
ふと気になったら手をだそう
whenever something catches my eye, I'll reach right out!
ほらね 一緒に遊ぼう！
Look, let's play together!
10連ガチャ引いてみよう
Let's try pulling the 10-pull gacha!
ホラーゲームやってみよう
Let's try playing a horror game!
あの曲歌ってみよう
Let's try singing that song!
ぜんぶがもう楽しいの
Everything is already so much fun!
窓の向こうの笑顔に手を振っちゃう！
Waving goodbye to the smiles beyond the window!
アニメ視聴中
Watching anime
推せるポテンシャル
Discovering hidden potential to stan
冷めない漫画や既読
Unfading manga and unread texts,
思いついた死にネタ爆笑
coming up with sudden tragic ideas and laughing out loud!
当たらない天気予報もきっと
Even inaccurate weather forecasts will surely
おもしろいことになるんだよ
turn into something hilarious!
聞いてみて今日のお散歩でさ
Listen, during today's walk,
見知らぬ猫と目があったの
I locked eyes with a stray cat!
珍しく喋っちゃったのは
The fact that I uncharacteristically started talking to it
すごく楽しって気づけなかったんだ
was because I hadn't realized how much fun I was having!
遠いことなんてそんなからないリアル
Reality isn't as far away as you think
だけどそのステージ
But on that stage
かぞその世界 夢に変えて
turning that world into a dream
毎日が宝物
Every day is a treasure
思い切り遊んで笑っちゃおう！
Let's play to our heart's content and laugh!
弁当おなかす 覚悟してきた
I came prepared with an empty stomach
何れこれ
What on earth is this?
立てる気がしないだって
I feel like I can't even stand
諦めたら実況終了だよ
If you give up, the stream's over!
まだ終わりたくない！
I don't want it to end yet!
どんな毎日も楽しくなっちゃうんだ
Any kind of day becomes fun and exciting!
だって、いつだって
Because, always,
ほらあなたが待ってるの！
Look, you are waiting for us!
みんなで毎日を出会えた嬉しいを
The joy of meeting everyone every day
みんなと一緒に 気分はね、もう最高潮！
Together with everyone, our mood is at its peak!
窓の向こうの笑顔に手を振って
Wave to the smiles on the other side of the window
配信でとどける あわてにだいありー
Delivering through our stream, our hurried daily diary
青春実況中！ さあ挑戦配信中！
Live streaming youth! Now challenging stream!
でいり～だいあり～！ 届けよう！
Deiri Daiari! Let's deliver it!
はーい！うまくいきましたね！
Yay! That went well!
いきましたね！いきましたね！
It went well! It went well!
はい！ていう いつも言っちゃうんだけど、
Yes! So— as we always say,
ということで！
and so!
かなとと獅白みででいり～だいあり～を歌わせていただきましたー！
Kanata and Shishiro sang 'Deiri Daiari'!
おめでとー！おめでとー！おめでとー！おめでとう！
Congrats! Congrats! Congrats! Congratulations!
ありがとーございます！いや、かなともこの前おめでと…あそっか！
Thank you so much! Kanata, congrats to you too recently... Oh right!
ありがと！おめでと！
Thanks! Congrats!
ということで、そしてあけましておめで…あけましておめでとうございます！
And so, Happy New... Happy New Year!
いや、なんのかんだ、かなとことか獅白みとか
Well, anyhow, with Kanata, Shishiro, and—
そういう組み合わせあったけど、この4人で集まることは…そうね、初めてか？
We've had those combinations before, but gathering as these four... right, is it the first time?
初めて？そう！なんで…え、なんでみんなそんな後ろ行ってんの？
First time? Yeah! Why... wait, why are you all standing so far back?
もうちょっと前来てよ！そうだよね！どうなのこれ、並び結構いい感じじゃない？
Come a bit forward! That's right! How is this lineup? It feels pretty good, doesn't it?
どう？どう？なんか見たことあるようで実実は初めてなんだよ。
How? It looks familiar, but it's actually the first time.
あれ、この4人でコラボしたことあるよねって言ったら、いや、ない！って。
When someone said 'You've collaborated with these 4 before, right?', they went 'No way!'
ないわ！ないのか！じゃ掛け取りとかしたいね。お？じゃ掛け取りとかしたい！
No we haven't! We haven't? Then we want to match outfits. Oh? Then we want to match!
え、じゃさ、え何？金太のファッションの、え？今のファッションしてくれたりするんですか？
Wait, so, what? Kanata's fashion... will you style us in your current fashion?
え、ちょっと！いや、ファッションね！お買い物行きますかじゃあ！
Wait a minute! Fashion, huh! Shall we go shopping then?
お買い物行きたーい！じゃあこの中の一番おしゃれなの誰だと思う？
I wanna go shopping! Who do you think is the most fashionable among us?
あーー！いやや、これは論外！おろしせ、おろしせ！
Ahhh! No way, that's out of the question! Cut it out, cut it out!
許されへんぞ！やっぱりラミィかな？いや、でもこれとわ先輩だってファッションのプロフィールから書いたしさ。
Unforgivable! Is it Lamy? No, but Towa-senpai even wrote it in her fashion profile.
いや、ファッションは…もう、やめろ、やめろ！
Well, fashion is... stop it, stop it!
すみません！すみません！ちょっと待って…とわ様、この洋でちょっと写真みたいなスクショみたいに…
Sorry! Sorry! Wait a minute... Towa-sama, like this, let's take a photo or screenshot...
スクショ撮りたい！じゃあ並んで並んで…ちょっと、まいこ。あ、じゃあこう後ろ行こうかな？
I want to take a screenshot! Line up, line up... Wait, Maiko. Ah, then let's go to the back?
はーい、じゃあはーい！いえーい！
Okay, then, yay!
いい感じじゃなーい？いい感じよ！撮って！撮って！
Doesn't it feel good? It feels good! Take it! Take it!
あれ、急にテンションダウン？いや、お祝いだからさ、いいんだよみんなとお祝いできればいいから。
Huh, energy suddenly dropped? Well, since it's a celebration, as long as we can celebrate with everyone, it's fine.
そんななんかすごいお祝いモードとかになっても別に…まあ、これからもよろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Even if it turns into a huge celebration mode... well, thank you for your continued support! Thank you!
生意気な後輩と…生意気じゃないが！すごい生意気なふたりと！
An impudent junior and... I'm not impudent! Two very impudent ones!
生意気じゃないが！生意気なふたりと…天使だね！
You're not! Two impudent ones... and an angel!
神戸と天使でセンスがね、完璧な神戸と…耳がよく聞こえないな！
Kanata and angel have perfect sense... I can't hear well!
耳痛くなった、新しい！…はい！ということで…
My ears hurt, that's new!... Yes! And so...
かなとと獅白みで、でいり～だいあり～でしたー！いえーい！バイバイン！バイバーイ！
Kanata and Shishiro Botan, that was 'Deiri Daiari'! Yay! Bye-bye!
胸騒ぎほらメリーゴーランド
A fluttering heart, look, a merry-go-round
夢のようなスピードでエスコート
Escorting at a dream-like speed
時の流れはいつでもゆっくり
The flow of time is always slow
だけどハートの動くスピード気まぐれワープ
But the heart's moving speed is a whimsical warp
届くよ この場所へ
Reaching you, to this place,
ちゃんと届くように
so that it reaches you properly.
キミのclap-clap-clap
Your clap-clap-clap,
Everybody Clap Hands Up
空想へドライブ★
Drive to fantasy★
Moonlight Merry-Go-Round
Candy-Go-Round
Ready-Go-"Live"
夢のようなスピードで飛び立てば
Take off at a dreamlike speed,
歌に乗り込めば行けるんだ
you can go if you get into the song.
タイムスリップ もう止められない
I can't stop time slip anymore.
Starlight Merry-Go-Round
Candy-Go-Round
Parallel-World はじまりのベルが鳴り響く夜に 迎えに行くから
Parallel-World, I'll pick you up at night when the beginning bell rings.
同じビートで ひとつのナンバー
With the same beat, play one number
奏でよう
together.
心を1ミリでも動かせば キセキ起こす 大きな1歩に繋がるから
If you move your heart even by 1 millimeter, it leads to a big step that causes a miracle.
つまらないときは 「わくわく」をクリックしてみよ
When it's boring, try clicking "Wakuwaku".
キミと dance×dance×dance
Dance×dance×dance with you
(Everybody Shall We Dance?) ステップ踏んで パーティーしよう！
(Everybody Shall We Dance?) Let's step and have a party!
Stand up Ring-a-bell
Fairy-tail Wonderland-"Live"
出掛けたい場所へ 連れてくよ
I'll take you to the place you want to go.
妄想トリップ もう止められない
I can't stop delusion trip anymore.
Start line Ring-a-bell
Fairy-tail Colorful-Night
どんな距離だって 越えて会いに行く
Crossing any distance to go meet you.
夜空を見上げて ドラマチックで忘れられない
Looking up at the night sky, make it a dramatic, unforgettable
今にしよう
present.
起きてても覚めない 魔法かけるから はじめよう ステージを
I'll cast a spell that you won't wake up from even if you awake, let's begin the stage.
キミの胸のドキドキ 嘘じゃないよ リアルだよ
The pounding in your chest, it's not a lie, it's real.
星もうれしく飛び回って リズムを合わせるように
Even the stars are happily flying around to match the rhythm.
とびきりな夢を キミと キミと キミと キミと キミと一緒に
With an exceptional dream, together with you, you, you, you, and you.
Moonlight Merry-Go-Round
Candy-Go-Round
Ready-Go-"Live"
夢のようなスピードで飛び立てば
Take off at a dreamlike speed,
歌に乗り込めば行けるんだ
you can go if you get into the song.
タイムスリップ もう止められない
I can't stop time slip anymore.
Starlight Merry-Go-Round
Candy-Go-Round
Parallel-World はじまりのベルが鳴り響く夜に
Parallel-World, I'll pick you up at night when the beginning bell rings
迎えに行くから 同じビートで ひとつのナンバー
with the same beat, play one number.
奏でようよ
Let's play!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
ちょっと待って！トワ様さ、練習と違うやん！
Wait a minute! Towa-sama, that's different from rehearsal!
え？何のこと？みんなで練習したじゃんね？
Eh? What are you talking about? We all practiced together, right?
そこはほら、せーの、うー！
Right there, ready, set, woo!
あそこさ、こういう感じでかわいく「ぴょん！」って言ってたじゃん！
Right there, you were saying "Pyon!" so cute like this!
え？そ、何のこと言っての？
Eh? Wh-, what are you talking about?
せーの、うー！
Ready, set, woo!
あのさ、みんな見てるコメントも分かるけど、トワはずっとこうやってさ！
You know, everyone watching the comments can tell, but Towa has been doing this the whole time!
何が、何の話なの？
What, what are you talking about?
えーとわがトイレに行ってる時に、今晩これでやろうって言ってたんだよ！
When Towa went to the restroom, she said we'd do it like this tonight!
届きり大成功！いぇーい！
Complete success! Yay!
マジでびっくりしたんだけど！
I was seriously surprised!
急にこの中すごく可愛くやってたのにさ、急になんか...
Suddenly everyone was doing it so cute, but suddenly...
逆にその動きできないんだけど！やってごらん！
I can't even do that movement in reverse! Try doing it!
まずはこの2ステップの感じからだんだんだいたんに！
First, from this two-step feeling, gradually and boldly!
ほい！ほい！ほい！ほい！可愛い！ほい！ほい！ほい！ほい！
Hoi! Hoi! Hoi! Hoi! Cute! Hoi! Hoi! Hoi! Hoi!
いやとわ輝いてるよ！
No, Towa, you're shining!
今日はこんなことで呼びたくなかったのにさ！
I didn't want to call you out for something like this today!
2周年おめでとーって言って、ほら可愛いから、おめでとー！
Say "Happy 2nd Anniversary", look, because it's cute, congratulations!
やりすぎ！おかしーな！
Too much! That's weird!
お願い？
Please?
お年玉、僕たちにとって精一杯のお祝いだったんだけど！
That New Year's gift was the absolute best celebration we could give!
なんでだよ！
Why'd you say that?!
なんか、聞き入れられないのが悪い意味で…
It's just... in a bad way, like it wasn't accepted...
もう仲間じゃん！だってできるようになって…できるようになったよ、ねぇ？
We're already friends! I mean, you can do it now... you can do it, right?
おかゆがさ、冒険のクエストのさ、もう君がそれができるようになったら仲間だねみたいな…
Like, Okayu, in the adventure quest... once you can do that, you're our friend, like...
なんかそういう風に見えてきたんだけど…そうじゃないよ。
It started looking like that... but that's not it.
大丈夫！チュートリアルも完璧だったし、大丈夫だよ！
It's fine! The tutorial was perfect, so it's all good!
大丈夫！大丈夫！
It's fine! It's fine!
行こう、行くぞ！
Let's go, let's go!
次は…お迎えと、みおちゃんと、ペコラちゃんと、トワでキャンディガーランドでしょ？
Next is... Oumae, Mio-chan, Pekora-chan, and Towa for Candy Garland, right?
お迎えと、みおちゃんと、ペコラちゃんと、トワでキャンディガーランドでしょ？バイバーイ！
Oumae, Mio-chan, Pekora-chan, and Towa with Candy Garland, right? Bye-bye!
いつの間にか見つけてた遠い夢
A distant dream I found before I even knew it,
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
scenery I couldn't have seen all by myself.
波打つ風の音と加速していく想いに
With the sound of rippling wind and accelerating feelings,
戸惑いを覚えた
I felt bewildered.
ずっと追いかけた理想の姿はまだ届かなくて遠いけど
The ideal form I've been chasing is still out of reach and far away, but
きっとこの瞬間をかけがえないみんなで共に行くよ！
I'm sure we'll go together with everyone in this irreplaceable moment!
手を繋いで
Holding hands,
3.2.1！
3, 2, 1!
輝き宿して夢の場所へ！
embedding our radiance, to the place of our dreams!
駆け抜けていく僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth as we dash through
誰にも止められないよ！
can never be stopped by anyone!
笑い合う分だけ優しく零れる涙さえ 今ほら輝かせ
Even the tears that spill so gently from laughing together, now make them shine.
明日へ運ぶから君の隣へ僕たちは世界を越えて行く
Carrying them toward tomorrow, by your side, we go beyond the world,
迎えに行くよまだ見えない明日もキラメキに変えてきっと
going to greet even unseen tomorrows, transforming them into sparkle, surely
僕たちが未来へと連れて行くから！
leading us on toward the future!
背伸びしては手を伸ばす憧れの行き先示す星になろう
Stretching up and reaching out, let's become the stars pointing to our longing.
躊躇うその度に手を差し伸べ合えたら
Whenever we hesitate, if we reach out our hands to each other,
すぐに届くはずさ
they're sure to reach each other right away.
そっと踏み出した小さな勇気がもう消えないように繋ごう
Let's connect the small courage we softly stepped forward with so it never fades.
不安も愛しさも大切に抱きしめて
Embracing both our anxiety and our affection dearly,
共に行くよ 目を合わせて 3.2.1！
we'll go together, locking eyes, 3, 2, 1!
晴れ渡る希望へ飛び出すよ！
Springing out toward clearing skies of hope!
突き抜けていく僕たちの透き通る決意はまだまだ止められないよ！
The crystal-clear resolve of our breakthrough can still not be stopped!
ありきたりな今日こそトキメキに変えていつでも僕たちが背中押すから！
Transforming ordinary days into excitement, we'll always be pushing you!
ずっと一人で描いてたキャンバスがいつからかコライトになって
The canvas I used to paint all alone someday became a co-creation,
また少しずつ芽生える大好きを紡ぎ
weaving together the things we love as they sprout little by little.
どこまでも高くあすいろの空へ駆け抜けていく僕たちの青春の光は
High into the sky of azure colors, soaring up, the light of our youth as we dash through
誰にも止められないよ！
can never be stopped by anyone!
笑い合う分だけ優しく零れる涙さえもっと
Even the tears that spill so gently from laughing together,
僕たちがいつまでも背中を押すから
we will keep pushing you from behind forevermore.
ずっと一人で描いてたキャンバスが
The canvas I used to paint all alone
いつからか怖いくらいの…人に（あるいは何かに）なって
someday became something almost frighteningly...
ネバーエンディング旅の続きを紡ぎ
weaving the continuation of our never-ending journey.
どこまでも高くあすいろの空へ
High into the sky of azure colors,
駆け抜けていく僕たちの青春の光は誰にも止められないよ！
the light of our youth as we dash through can never be stopped!
笑い合う分だけ優しく零れる涙さえ今ほら輝かせ
Even the tears that spill so gently from laughing together, now make them shine.
明日へ運ぶから君の隣へ僕たちは世界を越えて行く
Carrying them toward tomorrow, by your side, we go beyond the world,
迎えに行くよ
I will go to meet you
まだ見えない明日も
Even tomorrow that is yet unseen,
きらめきに耐えて きっと
enduring the brilliance, surely
僕たちが 未来へと
we will head toward the future,
果てのない 未来へと
toward an endless future,
連れて行くから
taking you along with us.
おおおー！いぇーい！
Ooh! Yay!
どうもー！いつもので！いつものね！
Hello! As usual! The usual one!
前回のお揃いさん時とに いつもトワは「ということで」をすっごい乱用してたから
During the last matching outfit time, Towa abused the phrase "Therefore" so much
この後何を言うかってすっごい迷った
and afterwards she was super worried about what to say next.
「ということで」を禁止を、「ということで」禁止令を、「ということで」を、あの、すごい白熱の時間があった
So we had a heated debate banning the phrase "Therefore".
え、ちょっとみんな揃うい…あ、いぇー！
Eh, everyone match… Ah, yay!
あ、やれやれ！やれやれ！やれ！やれ！やれ！やれ！やれ！やるか！
Ah, do it! Do it! Are we doing it?
えーと、えーと、トワたち せーの！「スタッフです！」
Um, um, Towa and the others, ready, set! "We are the staff!"
ここだ！スタッフです！スタッフです！スタッフです！
Right here! Staff! Staff! Staff!
まるで…まるでさ、ちゃんとできたっていう意識があって
It's like… feeling like we did it properly
忘れてて
but we forgot!
確かに！いや、そうなんです。
That's true! Yeah, that's right.
意外なメンバーなんだけど
It's an unexpected member, but
あのブルームで、そのアス色クリアスカイ…あ、トワはちょっと歌っちゃったんだけど、アス色クリアスカイを歌ってない3人
in Bloom, the three who didn't sing "Asuiro Clear Sky"…
あゆちゃん、あゆちゃんって、すいちゃん、あゆちゃんとフブちゃん歌ってない3人を集めて「シャッフルユニット」っていう形でやらせていただきました！
we gathered Suisei, Ayame, and Fubuki—the three who didn't sing it—as a "shuffle unit"!
いや、どうだった？めちゃめちゃよかったのよ！
How was it? It was super good!
めっちゃよかったよね。
It was really good.
イベントバランスすごいよかったよね。
The event balance was really good.
楽しかった！でも高かったでしょ？
It was fun! But it was high, right?
高かった！
It was high!
めっちゃ切り上げりゃん！
It jumps right up!
果てのない未来へ向けて歌っていくから
Because we'll sing toward an endless future,
そんな苦しさは感じさせない
we won't let you feel that hardship.
え、なんかすごいダンスもさ、簡単ではあるけどみんなですっごい揃ってさ、綺麗だったよね。
The dance was simple, but everyone was so in sync and it was pretty.
よかったよね。ありがとうございました！
It was good. Thank you very much!
いつも通りが言いな。そうですね、今年もよろしくお願い…
As usual is good. Yes, please look forward to this year as well…
毎回これを言う感じ、お願いしまーす。
Saying this every time, please.
あけましておめでとうございます！よろしくお願いいたします！
Happy New Year! Thank you very much!
最後ちょっとみんなで写真撮らない？
Shall we all take a picture at the end?
え、じゃあこれですか？
Eh, is it this?
え、さっきの撮ってないか。撮ってない！これバージョンと
Ah, we didn't take the previous one. We didn't! This version and
違うバージョン。はい、スタッフ！
a different version. Yes, staff!
トワ様2周年おめでとう！おめでとう！ありがとー！
Towa-sama 2nd anniversary congratulations! Congrats! Thank you!
かわいいバージョンも撮って。
Take a cute version too.
もっとよろうよ。あ、いい感じ。
Let's gather closer. Ah, nice feeling.
いぇい！いえーい！いぇい！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
いつもの通りがいいな。そう、いつもの通りがいいね。
As usual is good. Yeah, as usual is good.
ということで！
Therefore!
いや、絶対ユウだと思った。絶対ユウだと思った。
I totally thought it was Yuu.
めっちゃ噛んだときの反応が…
The reaction when she stumbled so much…
はい、きたー！ということで！
Here it comes! Therefore!
では、すいちゃんとあゆちゃんとふぶちゃんとトワね、アス色クリアスカイでしたー！
So, Suisei, Ayame, Fubuki, and Towa, that was "Asuiro Clear Sky"!
ありがとう！ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
ゲストパートはいかがだったでしょうか？
How was the guest part?
すごいよかったんじゃないですか。トワはやっぱりプロデュースセンスがあるんじゃないかなと勝手に思っております。
I think Towa has great producing sense.
ゲストパートというか、そういう色、でもすごいいろいろあったんだよ。ね、スタッフさん。
Regarding the guest part, there were so many things. Right, staff?
みんな、いろいろあった上で
After going through a lot,
今回こういう感じで、すごいエモいのができました！裏話を聞きたい人は後日配信を…
we created something so emotional! For those who want to hear behind-the-scenes stories, check the stream later…
配信をするので、よかったら後日配信に遊びに来てね！
I'll be streaming, so please come visit the stream later!
ゲストめちゃよかった！ありがとー！
The guests were amazing! Thank you!
ねぇどうもみんな本当にとっても良かったです。
Hey everyone, thank you all so much.
まあ、そのゲストの話は後日するとして、
Well, as for the guest, we'll talk about that later,
ま、皆さん、これぐらいの時間だったらわかると思いますよね。
but I think you all know by now given the timing, right?
はい、何があるか？はい、こちら！
Yes, what could it be? Yes, here!
なだれのように！はい、グッズです！
Coming in like an avalanche! Yes, merch!
どうせ来年の頭も頭ちょっとやばいかもしれない。
Anyway, maybe early next year is going to be crazy too.
はい、2周年記念グッズが発売されます！4種類ありまして、
Yes, 2nd anniversary merch is going on sale! There are 4 types:
ランダムのラバーストラップ、トワのモチーフのボディバッグ、
random rubber straps, a Towa motif body bag,
あとは金属の3連ブレスレットと、あとはマスクが入ったセットをフルセット買っていただきますと、
and a set including a 3-strand metal bracelet and a mask. If you buy the full set,
サインとメッセージ入りのダイカットポストカードがあなたの手元に入ります。
an autographed and message-included die-cut postcard will come to your hands.
トーク、トーク力よ！今年もねトーク力を期待していきたいと思っております。
Talk, my speaking skills! I hope to live up to your expectations in speaking this year too.
はい、では細かい内容はこちら！どう！
Yes, now the detailed contents are right here! Ta-da!
ランダムストラップは、こちら4種類ありまして、
For the random straps, there are 4 types here,
見て、アイドル衣装のトワとお正月衣装のトワ、あとは通常衣装のトワと、あと私服のトワっていうことで、トワ尽くしになっておりますけれども、こちらごとう先生に書いていただきました。
look, Towa in idol outfit, New Year's outfit, normal outfit, and casual clothes, so it's all about Towa! These were illustrated by Goto-sensei.
可愛くない？
Isn't it cute?
いいね。これね、
Nice. This, you know,
あの、いっぱい、実はね、本当はね、あのし、アイドル衣装2種類とか、
actually, there were really two types of idol outfits,
お正月衣装2種類とか、色々書いてくれたんだけど、もうめちゃめちゃ最後まで悩んで、
two types of New Year's outfits, and various others drawn, but after agonizing until the very end,
この4種類にさせていただいたんで、みなさんよかったらランダムになってしまうんですけど、
we narrowed it down to these four types. So everyone, if you're willing, though it's random,
個別でも売ってるので是非買ってください。
we also sell them individually, so please check them out.
はい、次！
Yes, next!
これこれみんな、ボディバッグ！これです。
This one everyone, the body bag! This is it.
めっちゃこれ、この、これぐらいの大きさの胸ぐらいのよくあるじゃない？
Super- this—around this size, chest-level kind of thing you often see, right?
あるじゃない？なんかおば、おば、あれちょっと、おば？
Right? Like, grandma- wait, grandma?
よくないでしょ？そう、そのね、
That's not good, right? Right, so,
リュックサックとかもいいなと思ったんだけど、トワ結構この斜め掛けのこのミニポーチ、ちょっと、ちょっとした出かけるときに、こういうバッグがすごい、ま個人的に、トワが欲しかったからっていうのもあるんだけど、
I thought rucksacks were also nice, but Towa really likes this diagonal mini pouch, when going out a bit, having a bag like this is great—well, personally, partly because Towa wanted it too,
はい、これね、ミニモチーフボディバッグも発売されます。
yes, this mini motif body bag will also be released.
これめっちゃんこね、あのね、普段使いしやすいような形で作成していただいてるので、ぜひ
It's super- made in a shape that's easy for everyday use, so please
よければどうぞ。基本的に全部あの個別で売ってるので、よかったら2個欲しいっていう方もこれ個別で買ったりとかしてくださいね。
go ahead. Basically they're all sold individually, so if you want two, you can buy them individually too, okay?
はい、じゃ3つめ、どん！
Yes, then the third one, ta-da!
はい、金属3連ブレスレット！
Yes, 3-strand metal bracelet!
これはね、ここの手首に手首につけるやつでございます。
This is something you wear on your wrist here.
おしゃれだよね。トワのね尻尾もイメージしてありますので、
It's stylish, right? It's also designed with Towa's tail in mind,
イメージカラーと尻尾をブレスレットにしていただけました！
so they made it into a bracelet with the image color and tail!
すごいグッズもね、トワがやっぱり、あの、
For the goods too, Towa really, um,
普段使いできるようなとか、結構おしゃれなものを今までグッズとして販売していたので、今回もおしゃれなものが出したいんですっていうふうにご相談したらおしゃれにしてくれました！
wanted something usable for everyday life, and until now we've sold quite stylish items as merch, so when I consulted them saying I wanted to release something stylish this time too, they made it stylish!
イエイ、はい。
Yay, yes.
じゃ次、はい、どうぞ。
Then next, yes, please.
はい、4つ目はマスク！
Yes, the 4th is a mask!
はい、今のご時世大事です。皆さん、どうぞ！
Yes, very important in this day and age. Everyone, please!
はい、全部買って、全部フルセットを買うと、
Yes, if you buy all of them, buy the full set,
そう、はい、こちら4種類のね、先ほどのミニイラストに、ミニイラストがね、あの、なんかすっごい、なんていうのこれ、あのダイカットっていうらしいよのポストカードがついてきます！
right, yes, for these 4 types, the mini illustrations from earlier—the mini illustrations have, um, a die-cut postcard attached!
メッセージはね、秘密中！
The message is, a secret!
キモ、秘密！
Gross, it's a secret!
これです。
This is it.
教科書しいからさ、ちょっと今スタッフさんにさ、ちょっと、あの、苦笑いされながら説明してるから、すいません！これです！
Because it's embarrassing, the staff is kind of smiling wryly while I explain, so sorry! This is it!
はい、ということでグッズセットがありますよっていうお話ですと、
Yes, so that's the story that there is a merch set,
今日おかしいんだわ、まあ、昨日地獄味わってるから仕方ないよね。
today is weird, well, I experienced hell yesterday so it can't be helped.
ね、昨日というか今日、まあ昨日だよね。昨日ね、はい、パパ、パパ金なんで、はーい。
Right, yesterday or rather today, well it was yesterday. Yesterday, yes, papa, papa gold, so yes.
はーい、ということでなんと、なんと、告知はこれだけじゃないんです。重大告知が皆さんあるんです。
Yes, so what, what, the announcements don't stop here. There is a major announcement for everyone.
では、重大告知！どん！どん！
Now, major announcement! Ta-da! Ta-da!
はい、常闇トワ1st EPミニアルバム『Scream』の発売になりまーす！
Yes, Tokoyami Towa's 1st EP mini album "Scream" is going on sale!
これ、今誰も反応してくれてないのがすごい寂しいけど、みんなのコメントを見て、トワはわあってなってるっていうことをすごい思います。はい。
It's super lonely that no one's reacting right now, but seeing everyone's comments, I really think Towa is going "waa!". Yes.
と、なんと目標でありましたアルバムを形に
And, an album that was our goal taking shape...
そして出すことが決定されます さあ
And it's been decided that we'll release... Now then!
すごい大変だった すごい でもすごい楽しみでした はい
It was so tough! But it was also super exciting. Yes.
ま 6曲収録されておりまして スリさんの「AKUMA」 R Sound Designさんの「ミッドナイトランウェイ」
Well, it features 6 tracks in total: "AKUMA" by surii, "Midnight Runway" by R Sound Design,
Nikiさんの「Palette」とあともう一曲ですね 「FACT」 あとANCHORさんの
"Palette" by Niki, and another track, "FACT", and "Born to be real" by ANCHOR,
ボン・トウ・ビ・リアルとあとウッチーさんの「マイロア」の6曲全部書き下ろしになってます
and "Maylora" by Ucchii. All 6 tracks are newly written!
こちらね 1月3日今日ですね 9時 9時でいいんだよね そう9時に
This will be released today, January 3rd, at 9:00—9:00 is right, right? Yes, at 9:00.
発売されます 概要欄ね あのグッズもこっちの「Scream」のアルバムもどっちもあの概要欄更新されてるので 9時になったら皆さんチェックしてくださいなー！ はーい！
Both the merch and the "Scream" album links are updated in the description box, so please check them out at 9:00! Yay!
はい えーとジャケット ごめんなさい ジャケットのデザインは 泉K先生 泉K先生に
Right, um, the jacket—sorry! The jacket design is by Izumi K-sensei,
あとロゴは今日のね あのロゴと一緒に あとヒラギ先生に書いてもらってます！ すいません！
and the logo, along with today's logo, was drawn by Hiragi-sensei! Thank you!
時間がちょっと急ぎ足になってしまうんですが はい
We're running a bit short on time, but yes.
ではね このアルバムどんな曲が入ってるのかと 皆さんちょっと疑問に思う方もいると思うので
Now, I'm sure many of you are wondering what kind of songs are on this album,
これから歌っていきたいと思います！2曲歌うので ぜひ聴いてくだされば嬉しいです では 聞いてください 「AKUMA」
so I'll be singing them now! I'll perform two songs, so I hope you'll enjoy them. Now, please listen to "AKUMA".
全身素敵なバイオレット
Fully gorgeous in violet,
とんがって参上 悪魔って最強
Pointy and arriving, demons are the strongest.
あなたの背中に闇をつけ 小悪魔だって恐ろしい
Putting darkness on your back, even a little demon is terrifying.
完全極楽浄土を提唱
Advocating absolute pure land,
抗って細胞 振り切って最強
Resisting cells, pushing past to be the strongest.
自堕落症状鎖付き
With a decadent symptom chain,
あくまで秘密の種も付き
Along with secret seeds after all.
何千回も爪を研いで機を伺って
Sharpening claws thousands of times, watching for the chance.
洗脳完了これで誕生 永遠に尽くそうだろう
Brainwashing complete, born anew, I'll devote myself forever.
悪魔界伝令 はーいと唱えて
The demon realm's message, chanting "Here!"
どこ闇がないなら渦を巻くデビデビ
If there's nowhere dark, make it swirl, Debi-Debi.
不思議解明デビデビ墜落の底から人間解放
Mystery solved, Debi-Debi, liberating humans from the depths of the fall.
なんて常識がないなら奪われるデビデビ
If there's no such thing as common sense, it gets stolen, Debi-Debi.
悪魔なの？影を撃って悪魔界連盟はーい繋いで
Are you a demon? Shoot the shadow, Demon Realm Federation, connect!
完全無欠のバイオレット
Flawless violet,
切り込んでハイに 取り込んで倍に
Cutting in to get high, taking in to double it.
あなたの心に忍び込み 小悪魔だって恐ろしい
Sneaking into your heart, even a little demon is terrifying.
刻む我 奇を衒え ならば他に誰？敵は誰？メンション
Carving myself, acting eccentric, then who else? Who is the enemy? Mention.
下界旅 つける錠 あれば君等ナビ 期待してんぜ
Journey to the lower world, attaching locks, if any, you guys navigate, expecting much.
悪魔界連盟はーい繋いで 相手にならないとクラを巻く
Demon Realm Federation, connect! If you aren't a match, spinning webs.
デビデビご都合証明 デビデビ世界はフィクション
Debi-Debi convenient proof, Debi-Debi the world is fiction.
健全なモードなんて今だけは全てを恨めないデビデビ
A wholesome mode—only for now, I can't resent everything, Debi-Debi.
悪魔なの？闇を知って悪魔界連盟はーい
Are you a demon? Knowing the darkness, Demon Realm Federation, here!
消えない寂しさと癒せない傷をつけて歩みをとめないなんて ほう
Leaving unforgettable loneliness and unhealable wounds, and never stopping your steps, oh?
わかった人間は時代を制御占領して光を生み出した
Humans who understood took control of the era and generated light.
悪魔のような所業ね ああ 詠った文明で
Such demonic deeds, ah, in the civilization we sang of.
悪魔界伝令 はーいと唱えて
The demon realm's message, chanting "Here!"
どこ闇がないなら渦を巻くデビデビ
If there's nowhere dark, make it swirl, Debi-Debi.
不思議解明デビデビ墜落の底から人間解放
Mystery solved, Debi-Debi, liberating humans from the depths of the fall.
なんて常識がないなら奪われるデビデビ
If there's no such thing as common sense, it gets stolen, Debi-Debi.
悪魔なの？影を撃って悪魔界連盟はーい繋いで
Are you a demon? Shoot the shadow, Demon Realm Federation, connect!
相手にならないとクラを巻くデビデビご都合証明
If you aren't a match, spinning webs, Debi-Debi convenient proof.
デビデビ世界はフィクション健全なモードなんて今だけは全てを恨めないデビデビ
Debi-Debi the world is fiction, a wholesome mode—only for now, I can't resent everything, Debi-Debi.
悪魔なの？影を撃って悪魔界連盟はーい繋いで闇を知って
Are you a demon? Shoot the shadow, Demon Realm Federation, connect, knowing the darkness!
オーイヨエオ オーイヨエオ
Ooiyoeo, ooiyoeo...
やべぇ なんかやべぇ
Man, this is wild...
ヤツのお通りだ
It's coming through.
野生のままでビルディングの谷間を行く
Running through the canyon of buildings on pure instinct.
ツノもウロコもシッポも触覚も
Antlers, scales, tail, and antennae—
出して出して出して出したいのさ
I just want to let them all out!
群れからはぐれ 理解されなくても
Even if I stray from the pack and go misunderstood,
好きなもので満たしたいだけ
I just want to be filled with what I love.
世界トップクラスで
World top-class,
世界にひとつだけの
and the one and only in the world—
役に立たない牙と爪
these useless fangs and claws.
誰に言われたって変える気はねぇ
No matter what anyone says, I won't change a thing.
何語かわからない言葉で吠えろ！
Howl in a language no one can understand!
オーイヨエオ オーイヨエオ
Ooiyoeo, ooiyoeo...
だせぇ なんかだせぇ
Lame, so lame...
縦髪捨てて
Toss away the mane.
ワンレンボブ アシメに ドレッドもいいね
Blunt bob, asymmetry, dreadlocks are nice too.
誰もかれも空飛ぶの目指したなら
If everyone aims to fly through the sky,
あえて羽を捨て走ってもいいね
it's fine to deliberately shed your wings and run.
ライオンっぽくない ヒョウっぽくないって
"Not lion-like, not leopard-like"—
人間のお偉いさんが決めたの？
was that decided by some pompous humans?
世界トップクラスで
World top-class,
世界にひとつだけの
and the one and only in the world—
役に立たない牙と爪
these useless fangs and claws.
鉄格子だって跳ね越えて
Leaping right over steel bars,
閉じ込められる場所なんてないのさ
there's no place that can lock you away.
誰も生態は知らない 知ってるわけなんてない
Nobody knows our ecology, there's no way they could.
レッドリストにも載ってない生物さ
A creature not even listed on the red list—
ここまでおいで
come on over here!
君はどこまで見える？
How far can you see?
君はそこまで見える？
Can you see all the way there?
そこじゃないぜ もう
That's not it anymore!
世界トップクラスで
World top-class,
世界にひとつだけの
and the one and only in the world—
役に立たない牙と爪
these useless fangs and claws.
誰に言われたって変える気はねぇ
No matter what anyone says, I won't change a thing.
私の喉だけの私の吠えを
My throat alone, my unique roar!
オーイヨエオ オーイヨエオ
Ooiyoeo, ooiyoeo...
はい、どうでしたか？
Hi, how was that?
ゴリゴリな、ロックな曲、どうでしたでしょうか？
What did you think of this hardcore, rockin' song?
はい、あの、すごい、アイドル衣装でロックな曲とか、ま、似合わないとか、そういう意見もあると思うんですけども、そんなね、概念を
Yeah, um, with such an idol outfit doing a rock song, some might think it doesn't fit... but despite those notions,
トワは、これからも、これからもというか、なんだろう、ぶっ壊していきたいなと思っております。はい。いろんなね、世界が見えたらいいなっていう気持ちを込めて、今回のアルバムのタイトルは
Twa wants to continue—well, not just continue, but break through those boundaries from now on. Yeah. With the feeling that I hope you can see all kinds of worlds, the title of this album...
「サイコスクリーム」っていうタイトルにしました。はい。
is named "Scream". Yeah.
あの、時間ももうしてしまったので、本当に、本当に本当に本当にありがとうございます。本当に、本当にこうやって形にできたのは本当に皆さんのおかげだなと思っております。ありがとうございます。はい。
Um, we're out of time, so thank you so, so, so much. I really feel that being able to shape this like this is all thanks to everyone. Thank you so much. Yeah.
で、このあとは、最後一曲披露したいんですけれども、アルバムにね、収録される曲を歌います！
And after this, I'd like to perform one last song, which will be included in the album!
9時からね、この後9時からも投稿予約してるんですけど
From 9 o'clock, I have a scheduled post starting at 9 later, but...
プレミアム投稿するんで、そちらも是非見て聴いてくれたら嬉しいです！
there will also be a premium premiere, so I'd be happy if you could watch and listen to that too!
はい！3年目も、アルバムも、トワのことみんな本当によろしくお願いします！
Yes! For our 3rd year, the album, and Towa herself, I truly ask for your continued support!
では最後、nikiさんの作詞作曲「FACT」聴いてください。
And finally, please listen to "FACT", written and composed by niki.
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in the eternal darkness,
奏でる悲鳴を
playing a weeping scream...
聴かせて
Let me hear it.
さあ 爪を磨いたら
Come on, once you sharpen your claws,
まだ子供のようなあなたの為に
for someone like you who is still a child,
ああ 試したいなら
Ah, if you want to be tested,
その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in the eternal darkness,
甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
chewing sweet, sweet gum,
いくつもの後悔を捧げて
dedicating numberless regrets.
さりげない合図に隠れた 答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
The answer hidden in a casual sign, I'll make you understand it right away.
微熱な嘘にまみれた 拒んだままで受け入れてあげる
Engulfed in a feverish lie, I'll accept it just as you refuse,
ほら 悲鳴を
come on, let me hear your scream.
ごめんねのままで受け止めてあげる
I'll accept it while leaving you with apologies,
ほら 悲鳴を 聴かせて
come on, let me hear your scream.
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
Come on, once you snap your fingers,
この子猫のような私のためにお願い
please do it for a kitten like me.
ああ 喉が乾いたわ
Ah, my throat is thirsty,
薄紅の口に指を散らして
scattering my fingers across pale crimson lips.
狭い牢獄に閉じ込めたまま
Shut away in a narrow prison,
首輪に繋がれたいの? くだらないルールじゃ縛れない
do you want to be bound to a collar? Silly rules can't hold me back.
自由はすでにこの手の中にある
Freedom is already in the palm of my hand,
愛情では測れない
something affection cannot measure.
弱ったままで選ばせてあげる ほら 心を開いて
I'll let you choose while still weakened—come on, open your heart.
わからないふりをして寝ぼけてるの?
Are you sleepwalking while pretending not to know?
もっと熱い暗闇を見せてね? ね?
Show me even hotter darkness, won't you? Hm?
さりげない合図に隠れた 答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
The answer hidden in a casual sign, I'll make you understand it right away.
微熱な嘘にまみれた 拒んだままで受け入れてあげる
Engulfed in a feverish lie, I'll accept it just as you refuse,
ほら 悲鳴を
come on, let me hear your scream.
ごめんねのままで受け止めてあげる
I'll accept it while leaving you with apologies,
ほら 悲鳴を 聴かせて
come on, let me hear your scream.
常世の闇に刻むこの名を わからせてあげる
This name carved into the eternal darkness, I'll make you understand it.
ほら 悲鳴を 聴かせてよ
Come on, let me hear your screams!
夢見ないで ほら 聴かせて
Don't dream, come on, let me hear it.
ほら 聴かせて
Come on, let me hear it.